Wash It
All Away
Episode 4   A Personal Request from Kinme
We Pick Up and Deliver!
Kinme Cleaning
The Honmas take such good care
of their garden.
I haven't ridden the train in a while.
The doors are closing. Please stand clear.
Sh-She startled me!
Girls these days
sure wear their skirts short.
Barely covers anything.
With Green Tea Extract
Works for 48 Hours!
Finebreeze
Huh?
Y-You can't...
What?
You can't yank on a shirt like that!
Oh, dear. I knew it.
Aw, man.
Well, this sucks.
I'll just go like this from now on.
No, don't do that!
Next stop is Kinomiya. Kinomiya.
I mean, is this free?
Of course. You don't owe me anything.
I just can't ignore this sort of thing.
I run a cleaning business
near the station here.
My name is Kinme Wakana.
Huh...
And what is your name?
It's Wakasagi.
Wakasagi Kuriru.
But I mean, what are you doing outside?
Huh? Outside?
Cause, like, don't cleaners
work inside a shop?
Oh. Yes, I do most of my work at the shop,
but I also have many elderly customers,
so I often go out
for pick-ups and deliveries.
It's just a small, independent business,
but in keeping with our motto,
"Local Cleaning with a Heart," I like to
go out of my way for the customers.
Was that a sales pitch?
Huh?
Oh, no! Just talking.
There. Repairs complete.
Awesome! Just like that!
You're so ladylike! You must
have tons of boyfriends, Kinme-san.
Oh, no, not at all.
From now on, try to treat
your clothes with more care, okay?
Yeah, but I'm not really sure
what to do with them, you know?
I live with my brother, and we don't have
anyone around to fix things for us.
There's shirts all around the apartment
with missing buttons and stuff.
If it's all right with you, why don't I
stop by your home right now
and see what kind of condition
your clothes are in?
Huh?
Oh, but if this is a bad time,
that's okay.
I mean, like, I don't really mind, but...
But?
Right now, the place is kind of...
Go on in.
Oh, my phone charger's lying
around there somewhere, so watch out.
Those things can really hurt.
There are dirty clothes thrown everywhere.
How often do you usually do laundry?
Well, house rules say we each gotta
do our own, but it's such a pain.
Maybe about three times a month?
Oh dear.
Maybe I should help her
clean house as well.
Oh!
No, stop spraying!
You shouldn't use that so recklessly!
Huh?
With Green Tea Extract
Works for 48 Hours!
Finebreeze
Double
You sprayed that all over your uniform
on the train too, didn't you?
But I mean, sweaty-smelling
clothes are gross.
Yes, but you see, it's very common
to use sprays like that incorrectly.
What am I doing wrong?
With Green Tea Extract
Works for 48 Hours!
Finebreeze
Double
Antibacterial
Deodorant
I realize this sort of antibacterial
deodorant is common and convenient,
but if you spray a fabric
when it still has a sweat stain on it,
the spray liquid could make
the stain spread into a circular shape
and set into the fabric.
The smell may go away, but stains
will keep accumulating on the fabric.
If you use sprays like that regularly,
you need to be really, really careful!
Consider it a personal request from Kinme!
Oh. Uh-huh.
For daily care of your uniform,
you should hang your skirt
on a skirt hanger and brush it instead.
One benefit of brushing is that it gets
rid of dirt and dust stuck to the fabric.
Then it straightens out all
the little fibers that are so hard to see,
which also helps.
If you don't have a brush, it's fine
to use a lint roller or even packing tape.
Packing tape works for that?
I still think it is best to
wash occasionally, though.
Check the care labels to see which of
your garments are washable at home.
Wait, they tell you? But I mean,
what is a care label anyway?
Materials
Polyester
Wool
One of these. By the way,
New Symbols
Do Not Wash
Do Not Dry Clean
Do Not Wet Wash
if you see any of these symbols,
it means you cannot wash it at home,
so please take those items
to the cleaners.
Do Not Wash in Water
Cannot Dry Clean
Older clothes will have
the old versions of the symbols.
Old Symbols
* Cleaning symbols were updated
in December 2016.
Materials
Polyester
Rayon
Low
Use Net
Chlorine
Bleach
Medium
Dry
Petroleum-based
Yes, these are the old symbols.
Huh, they are kinda different.
I'd never even looked
at those things before.
But I mean, is it okay
to be telling me all this?
Huh? Why wouldn't it be?
Materials
Polyester
Rayon
Low
Chlorine
Bleach
Medium
Well, isn't it something
like a trade secret?
If everyone knew how to
take care of their own clothes,
they wouldn't go to your shop as much.
And then you'd lose out, right?
Not at all.
I'd be thrilled if everyone
took better care of their clothes!
Wow. You've got, like, maxed out
cleaning skills. You'd be such a catch.
Huh?
W-Well, could you show me
your clothes with missing buttons?
I think this is one.
Wow. This one appears to be
missing four buttons.
I know.
And it's winter wear. I'd recommend
that you got this cleaned as well.
Maybe I should.
However, if you don't mind me saying so,
perhaps we could clean your room first.
Get this. She didn't say, "Good morning."
She said, "Help me get these pajamas off."
Treating her little brother like a servant
or something. Can you believe it?
So what did you do?
I helped her out.
You did, huh?
And at first, we were
taking turns cooking each day,
but recently she's been making me
do all the cooking myself!
Hmm. So who's cooking tonight?
I guess I am.
You are, huh?
Still, your big sis sure is
a hit with the guys at school.
Yeah, 'cause none of them see
what she's like on the inside.
And I mean, we're twins and were
basically born at the same time,
so why does she always
act like she's older?
Yeah, you were saying that before.
Well, I actually don't care
that she's older,
but is it too much to ask for some
big-sisterly attributes at least?
Sisterly attributes, huh?
Yeah! Like being nice and reliable
and worshiping her brother!
Sounds like some kind of fantasy.
Of course it is!
Huh? I guess she's already home.
I'm back.
Oh, welcome home, Moruda-kun!
Uh, wait.
Do I stick it in here?
Uh, that actually goes here.
Yes, like that. Just go very slowly, okay?
My name is Kinme Wakana.
Your sister and I sort of
became friends at the station.
I hope you don't mind me being here.
Uh, sure.
Right now we're, well, washing your
sister's clothes along with some of yours.
Is that all right with you?
Yeah, s'all right with me.
Wait, is that Kyusho-kun?
Are you boys friends?
Um, what are you doing here, Kinme-san?
Bro, bro, bro, wait a second.
How the hell did you get to meet
my true big sister before I did?!
For some reason, I think it'd be
a little hard to explain right now.
Can we save it for later?
True sister?
You'd better tell me later.
Pay no attention to him.
Wash It All Away
Kinme Cleaning
Hello!
Well, hello, Nairo-chan.
Come on in.
Would you please wash these for us?
All right.
Um, um... how late are you open today?
Hmm?
Oh, it's almost closing time now.
It looks like you're my last customer.
Hmm?
Oh? What are those?
Aha! Have you been practicing
drumming for the Kogashi Festival?
Yes! I have rehearsal right after this!
And these are my very own drumsticks!
Wow. They're very nice.
And the festival is
right around the corner.
I went last year and saw all the floats.
They were really impressive!
Yes! This year I get to ride the float
for Grandmother's Asama district
and play the drum!
Hmm?
So I would really like you to come
with me tonight and watch our practice!
Huh? Th-Thank you for the invitation,
but I think I'd just get in the way.
It's not my district, either.
That's totally okay, though!
I'd like you to see how much my drumming
improved over the last two weeks!
Okay? Okay? Please come and watch!
All right, hurry up!
We always hold practice over here.
Oh?
It's Kinme-san! Whatcha up to?
My daughter invited her
to come watch practice.
I'm sorry. I hope that's all right.
It's good, it's good. Stay and watch.
Everything's set up now, boss!
Sweet! Then let's get started.
Like it or not,
we've only got two days left,
so let's give it our best shot!
All right!
Let's do this!
I see Ishimochi-san is the organizer for
Asama's Kogashi Festival activities.
Yes. There are always many floats
competing from different districts,
so she's out here every day,
doing her best to keep everyone motivated.
We'll start as soon as you're ready!
Let's fix up the parts we flubbed
yesterday and power through to the end.
I wonder if the inn does all right
without her there to serve dinner.
Yeah.
Guesthouse Inn Ishimochi
Hey, son. Can I get seconds?
Comin' up.
Ready!
Tam, tam.
Looking good.
Remember to get those sticks up.
Tam, ta-ta-tam.
Tam, tam, tam.
We actually moved here
from Tokyo just this past spring.
Tam, tam. Tam.
Oh, is that right?
Our house is in a district in the hills,
but since Nairo's grandmother lives
down here, they let her participate
in this district's festival activities.
I see.
I can see why she would be so excited
about being in her first festival.
Until now, she's only been able to watch.
Did you ever drum in the festival
when you were younger, Kinme-san?
No, I've only been here
for about two years or so.
Oh, so this isn't your hometown?
Where are you from?
Okay, stop! Once more from the top.
Um, actually...
Sup!
Well, well. So you two
finally decided to show up.
Come on and lend us a hand.
Nah, I mean, we're just
on our way back from the store.
Why not? Kyu will be showing up soon too.
No, I really have to get home.
Sorry, gotta pass.
We've also got
a real looker with us today.
Whoo!
Oh, it's the cleaning lady from before.
Sup!
Kinme-san! Wow, what a coincidence!
Were you doing some shopping together?
Huh? Oh, yeah! Can't say
she helped much, though.
Oh, I guess you get to participate in
the festival because you live so close.
Yes!
When the time comes,
I'll be on top of that float!
Huh?
Oh? Wow! I'm sure you'll do great!
She's the one!
The ideal big sister! She's a real angel!
Totally one of those oblivious devils
who ends up leading all the guys on.
Oh, that's right. It's about time
we pull the festival clothes out again.
Um, if it would help,
shall I go and get them for you?
Oh, you're a lifesaver!
Thanks so much, Kinme-san!
We keep them stored
at the community center.
Community center?
I'd be happy to show you where it is!
What? But didn't you say
you needed to get home?
Yeah, so he can start making dinner and—
No, it's okay! Totally okay!
They sure get along well.
Okay, one more time!
Ready!
Tam, tam!
Eyes on the drum!
So you two don't rehearse with the others?
No. Rehearsals are pretty much meant
for kids in middle school or younger.
Community Center
Oh, it's right in here.
In high school, you get to ride
on top and hype up the crowd,
so we basically just show up
and play it by ear.
Wait. What the hell are you doing here?
Bodyguarding.
Oh!
Body?!
Wow, this many people participate?
There aren't that many people
around now, though.
Oh, and those are our parents
when they were in high school.
And that's Kyu-kun's mom.
Huh. They look like a wild bunch.
I guess Kyusho-kun will be riding too.
In that case, I should probably go watch.
You're gonna have a lot of
competition, you know.
Huh?
He's got those rugged good looks,
but he's also got a sweet side,
so the girls have been
into him since grade school.
He gets tons of chocolate
on Valentine's Day every year.
And my brother gets zilch.
Keep your mouth shut.
Huh. I guess that makes sense.
Oh?
Hmm? Huh?
Oh! I'm not saying that
I see him that way, though.
Hmm?
He's just the son of one of my regulars.
Yeah, that's right! Kyu is no more
than a customer to Kinme-san.
Why would you even think
there's anything else going on?
Right, and you're a wannabe player
who isn't even on Kinme-san's radar.
I'm not a player! I'm pure at heart!
Anyway, can we get the clothes out
and go home? I'm starving.
Quit complaining.
You could try helping for once.
Gah! What the hell happened?
Eww. They're covered in moldy stains!
How could this happen?
It must be because of
that leak in the ceiling.
Oh crap.
Like, aren't we screwed?
The festival is day after tomorrow!
Let's just throw them all
in the washing machine and—
No, don't do that!
If you don't clean the stains
and mold before washing,
I don't think you'll ever get them out.
Then what can we do?
I'll treat the stains
and then wash them all myself!
Will you make it in time?
Maybe if I stay up all night.
All night? Will you be okay?
I'm used to pulling all-nighters
during the spring busy season.
I know you need these garments
for the festival, so...
You can count on Kinme!
Damn, she's so cool!
But I don't think we should make
Kinme-san do it all alone.
Kyusho-kun!
Hey, Kyu! You trying to insult
Kinme-san's cleaning skills?
No, not at all.
But it's our fault the outfits got dirty.
We didn't store them carefully enough.
We need to take responsibility for that.
So let's all help Kinme-san out.
We'll be done sooner,
and it'll make things easier for you.
I agree with Kyu-kun's suggestion!
Here, take a box.
Why me?
There's still more.
Fine. Whatever.
Thank you so much.
It actually did seem
a little overwhelming.
Okay, everyone. Thank you for helping!
Now let's get these ready
for the festival!
Translation:
Editing and Typesetting:
Michael Arnold
Ashley Barboza
Quality Control:
Translation Check:
Riley Dalton
Sriram Gurunathan
Episode 5  I Have a Feeling...
Next time is "I Have a Feeling..."